[mysterious music]
[air whooshes]
Huh, an invitation
to the Tournament
of the Sources?
[laughing] Oh, yeah!
[air whooshes]
-Whoo!
-[mysterious music]
[block thuds]
[mysterious music]
[dragons screeching]
[scroll thuds]
[mysterious music]
[dragons screeching]
[engine humming]
[suspenseful music]
[sniffs]
[flowers crunch]
[suspenseful music]
[dragons screeching]
-[Ninja slurps]
-[cup clinks]
[mysterious music]
-[air whooshes]
-[scroll thuds]
[mysterious music]
♪ Lost in the unknown,
so much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[air whooshes]
[suspenseful music]
[footsteps tapping]
You think this junk still works?
Cease the doubting, it will.
[laughing maniacally]
[electricity zapping]
[robot humming]
-[fireball thuds]
-Eat fire, you no-gooders!
The Red Ninja's here
to kick your butts!
Well, Red Ninja-ish.
Meet Wyldfyre!
-[suspenseful music]
-[fireball whooshes]
[suspenseful music]
[fireballs whooshing]
Oh, whoa.
[suspenseful music]
Get back here!
Maybe Kreel will like these
mechs better all burnt up.
[suspenseful music]
[fireballs whooshing]
-[Nya] Ninja go!
-[air whooshing]
Nya, so glad you're here!
Not that I needed help.
Uh... I didn't!
[fireballs whooshing]
[water whooshing]
Oh, yikes, a real Ninja!
Let us flee!
That hurt my feelings!
-[fireball whooshing]
-[suspenseful music]
I Red Ninja'd!
Kai would be honored
you're trying
to take up the mantle of
the Red Ninja, Wyldfyre.
He should be.
But maybe you should wait
until you get
a little more training.
You haven't mastered
Spinjitzu yet,
and I'd hate to
see you get hurt.
Wyldfyre does not get hurt!
You were on a crutch for weeks.
I mean, I don't
get hurt anymore.
Hasn't Lloyd been teaching you
to focus more on
your fire precision?
I'm precise.
I'm the most precise!
[robot crashes]
And what about your
weapon training?
There's more to being a
Ninja than Elemental Powers.
I'm the only weapon I need!
Besides, someone has to
carry on Kai's legacy!
It's okay if you miss him.
I do too, more than
you could imagine.
Pfft, I don't miss people.
I'm not emotional like that,
but if I did,
I'd probably miss Kai.
Who knows, maybe
being trapped forever
in the Nether-Space
isn't that bad?
Yeah, I knew that sounded
dumb as soon as I said it.
I just hope it's at least
a peaceful place for Kai.
[suspenseful music]
Ugh, this place is infuriating!
[exhales deeply]
[sighs]
[suspenseful music]
We have to be quiet.
If the rest of
the Forbidden Five
figure out we're trapped
in here with them,
it won't go well.
For us, I mean.
They'd probably
love destroying us.
[suspenseful music]
-[footsteps thudding]
-[Bonzle gasps]
-[ominous music]
-Huh?
I don't think they saw us.
Let's go this way.
Oof!
-[rocks clattering]
-[ominous music]
Maybe they didn't hear us.
[suspenseful music]
-[gasps] They heard us.
-Run!
[door creaks, thuds]
Mm, what's this, new recipe?
New to you:
Merlopian Berry Creme.
My best friend, Frak,
taught me how to make it.
Your best friend?
[Riyu whimpers]
Besides you two, I mean.
Frak was my bestie
before the Merge.
He was as big a ninja fan as me.
Wow, that's saying something.
He'd be so excited for me now.
But he moved away,
and we lost touch.
Mm, we'll always have this pie.
[Riyu slurps and gulps]
Okay, then, I'll make more.
I wanna bake everyone
a goodbye treat,
before you all head off to
the Tournament of the Sources.
"Goodbye treat?"
You're coming with us, right?
The Tournament is for
Masters of Elemental Powers.
You know, the kind of
powers I don't have?
You're the Elemental
Master of Pie!
Seriously, though,
you have to come.
You're part of the team.
It sounds amazing,
but there's no place
for me there, Sora.
-[wings flapping]
-[suspenseful music]
[Motion Dragon]
If you are going to enter
the Tournament of the Sources
to find the villain
behind these attacks,
I'd advise you all to find
a Master to lead you.
-[wings whooshing]
-[mysterious music]
[feet thud]
[mysterious music]
[wings whooshing]
Egalt, Rontu,
I've come for Zane.
Oh, and Wyldfyre wanted
me to give you this,
Janus Melon Stew.
[Egalt sniffs]
Mm, that was quite kind of her.
[suspenseful music]
Zane! [chuckles]
-[Zane yelps]
-Good to see you, too.
[Zane yelps]
I am in a training
exercise, Lloyd!
[suspenseful music]
[wings whooshing]
[Zane yelping]
[suspenseful music]
-[rocks thudding]
-[Zane grunts]
-[air whooshes]
-[rocks thudding]
You're too focused
on fighting back!
Try to harmonize with
the motion of the rocks!
-[air whooshing]
-[Zane yelps]
[suspenseful music]
[Zane grunts]
[air whooshing]
[body crashes]
[suspenseful music]
You did it! You mastered
Rising Dragon Technique!
Your last-minute guidance
was most welcome.
[Egalt] Despite
my initial misgivings,
all you Ninja have proven
yourselves to be true masters.
I just hope my Rising Dragon
is enough to combat
Shatterspin technique.
Well, now that you, me,
Kai, and Nya can do it,
at least we stand a chance
if we ever run into
Ras and his crew again.
But we have more
pressing problems now.
Someone killed the Matriarch
of the Mountain Dragons
and stole her horns.
They did the same
to two other dragons.
Why would someone
do such a thing?
We don't know.
But the Motion Source
Dragon came to us for help.
She fears whoever did this
is coming for the
Source Dragons next.
There must be grave danger
for a Source Dragon
to ask for aid.
If the Source Dragons
are destroyed,
it could mean
the end of everything.
Are there any suspects?
No, but we believe
whoever did it
is entering the
Tournament of the Sources,
which is why I'm here.
For most of my life, we had
a great master, Master Wu,
but we lost him in the Merge.
He disappeared or worse.
So I'm formally asking,
will you be our Masters in
the Tournament of the Sources?
-[suspenseful music]
-No.
Thank you. What?
[Egalt] We have nothing
more to teach you.
You, Lloyd, must be
the one to lead the Ninja.
It is your duty.
-But I'm no Master.
-No?
No!
-[Egalt roars]
-What are you doing?
-[foot thuds]
-[Lloyd panting]
[Zane yelps]
[suspenseful music]
-[Lloyd grunts]
-[wing crashes]
[Lloyd yelps]
[tail crashes]
[Lloyd grunting]
[suspenseful music]
-[air whooshing]
-[Lloyd grunts]
You just beat two
of the greatest warriors
that ever lived.
Granted,
we are not in our prime.
Now give me that stew.
You didn't spill a drop.
[slurping] Excellent.
You passed our test,
Master Lloyd.
[mysterious music]
My Master Wu was a true Master.
I'm not ready.
You've faced much
in your young life
and have lost much--
your master,
teammates, friends--
and because of that,
you fear you won't be
able to protect everybody.
Your heart is too big, Lloyd.
Which is exactly why
you must lead the Ninja.
It is why you are
the one to carry on
the legacy of your
beloved Master Wu.
But what if I face
a problem I can't handle?
What if I fail?
We have faith you will
rise to the challenge,
Master Lloyd.
You always do.
Is this really necessary?
The Dragon Masters showed me
there are benefits
of stew-jitzu.
Huh, get it?
Ugh.
Come on, let's go!
-[air whooshing]
-[suspenseful music]
[whimsical music]
[slurping] What?
I like what I like:
stew.
[Riyu slurping]
So, Lloyd, I just wanted
to tell you, the tournament.
I, uh, I'm not gonna go.
I don't have an Elemental Power.
Arin, we're not going to
the tournament to win.
-We're not?
-Well, unless we have to win
to bring the Matriarch's
attacker to justice.
Someone killed those dragons
and stole their horns.
It's up to us
to find out who and why.
Which means you might have
the most important job of all.
To solve the mystery
while you all compete?
Exactly. The Motion
Dragon is relying on us,
and I'm relying on you, Arin.
Okay, that I can do.
My parents were
huge mystery fans,
always reading detective books,
teaching me how
investigations work.
This is all me...
and now I won't feel so
useless at the tournament.
You're never useless, Arin.
Now get packing.
It's time for us to go.
[mysterious music]
[engine roaring]
[grunts] We're here.
According to the
Motion Source Dragon,
that waterfall is the way
to the tournament somehow.
We're gonna meet all kinds
of new Elemental Masters!
Ah, this is gonna be so cool.
Remember, not every
Master is an ally.
-Cinder could be here, or--
-Euphrasia.
Yes, she might be here,
but she is our friend.
I am only listing enemies.
Not might be.
She is here, look!
[air whooshing]
[suspenseful music]
-[slot rumbles]
-[scroll clinks]
[door rumbles]
[suspenseful music]
[Cole] Whoa!
[squeals] Could
this get any cooler?
And you were thinking
about not even coming.
Let's go.
[Nya] Guess the tournament
is on top of that cliff?
So, let's do this.
Uh, how do we do this?
[mysterious music]
Take us to the tournament!
Please?
Euphrasia put something
in here, some kind of scroll.
Hey, look at this!
Hello, can anyone hear me?
[mysterious music]
We are here for the tournament!
[door rumbling]
Hello, I am Bleckt,
Minister of Ledgering
for the Tournament
of the Sources.
Great, and you're in charge
of the guest list, sir?
Not just the guest list,
all lists, tabulations,
Itineraries, agendas,
and inventories
fall under my duties
with the ledger.
The tournament has been run
by my family for
generations untold.
For each tournament, our city
would rotate to another Realm,
and invitations would go
out by spirit dragon courier
to all Elemental Masters there.
Although now all
the Elemental Masters
are in the same Merged Lands.
So more invitations have
gone out than ever before.
Well, it appears your spirit
dragons didn't get to us.
Oh, well, there's a simple
solution to that.
Great, 'cause I was afraid
this was gonna be a whole thing.
The solution is you go away.
If you didn't get an invitation,
you are not invited.
My dude, we're definitely
esteemed Elemental Masters,
so we must be invited.
Please don't make a fuss.
From the look of you,
you wouldn't be up to the
challenge of the games anyway.
Whoa, who are you, the
Elemental Master of Shade?
No, that's the Elemental
Master of Shade.
Welcome, Mistress Obscuria!
See you in the City of Temples.
[door rumbles]
[mysterious music]
Now please leave
and stop wasting my time.
[door closes loudly]
Oh, man, I was
really hoping to see
who's at the tournament.
We're not done yet.
[suspenseful music]
[slot rumbles]
[scroll clinks]
[air whooshes]
[Nya] Now!
[suspenseful music]
[metal clangs]
[tires screeching]
[Arin] We're doing it!
I knew we'd find a way-- [yelps]
Warning, warning,
intruder alert!
[Zane] This situation
is less than optimal.
[guns firing]
[Wyldfyre] We're intruders?
You're intruding
on our intrusion! Eat fire!
Uninvited guests
are not permitted
in the City of Temples.
-[guns firing]
-[suspenseful music]
[Arin] Abandon
ship, or, uh, car!
-[guns firing]
-[Sora grunts]
[Security Bot] This unit
has an unauthorized rider!
[suspenseful music]
[Arin] Hey, whoa!
Let's see how you like
an Elemental tech remix!
-[Sora yelping]
-[air whooshing]
[grunts] Great,
their tech must be so old,
my powers don't work
on it or something.
[air whooshing]
[stones crunching]
-[guns firing]
-[Jiro roaring]
[Lloyd] Sounds
like a plan, Jiro!
Off the dragons, onto
the wall, everyone!
-[air whooshing]
-[suspenseful music]
Looks like we have to climb
the rest of the way up.
[Wyldfyre gasps]
-Oh, no, I'm gonna barf.
-You ride dragons.
How are you possibly
afraid of heights?
Dragons are the safest
and most solid thing
to stand on ever!
This is not!
[air whooshes]
Arin, Arin, has
anyone seen Arin?
I thought I saw him hitch
a ride straight to the top
on one of those flying bots.
Riyu went after him.
I hope he's okay.
[metal clangs]
[grunts]
[panting, grunting]
[suspenseful music]
-[Spectator 1] Hey!
-[Spectator 2, laughing]
Whoo-hoo!
[Spectator 1] Yeah, ha!
People are watching us?
[door rumbles]
[Sora] The gates!
-[Roby vocalizing]
-Your arrival was--
Awesome, incredible,
massively driving engagement!
-Undignified!
-Are you kidding?
Sure, it was different
than the other competitors,
which is exactly
what these games need!
These Ninja are disruptors!
Disruption does not impress me.
Ugh, Uncle Bleckt, it's time
to shake this tournament up!
We've established millennia
of sacred traditions!
We do not shake anything up!
Guards, arrest them!
[suspenseful music]
Uh, uh, uh, who's
in charge here?
Who is in charge here, that kid?
Great to meet you! I'm Roby,
the new Master of Ceremonies
of the Tournament of Sources.
No big deal, but this
is kind of my event now,
and it's a big deal.
My folks retired to
the Kingdom of Madness.
There are amazing deals
on real estate there right now.
They couldn't pass it up.
And they left this
tournament to me.
Your uncle doesn't seem
too pleased about that fact.
Yeah, Uncle Bleckt
is a bit of um, mm--
Wet dragon tail?
If that's your cute way of
saying stick in the mud, 100%.
And I have big plans
to update this tournament.
Consider me the Elemental
Master of Surprise!
J-K, J-K, J-K.
Anyway, this year
is just the beginning
of what's gonna
become a multi-media,
cross-platform content
generating event,
and you, my Ninja, are
now part of my plan.
Don't know what happened
to your invitations,
but you are officially
invited by me,
the Roby himself, to compete.
Welcome to the tournament!
Bah-bah, bah-bah, bah-bah!
-Now behold the City of Temples!
-[Wyldfyre gasps]
A mix of retro
and new, cool, right?
And the games
haven't even started!
Got some big
surprises for later.
This is incredible and all,
but we've got a bigger problem.
Where are Arin and Riyu?
-[flashlight humming]
-[Riyu whimpers]
This is all just
a misunderstanding!
Our invitations
got lost, I swear!
[Frak] Arin, is that you?!
[Arin] Frak?
Oh-ho, it is you!
I haven't seen you
since before the Merge!
[upbeat music playing]